Guide to the Graduate School of Social Work
University of Houston Libraries
Graduate School of Social Work Records
1960-2009
2009-018
University of Houston. Graduate School of Social Work
2.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contain 2 boxes of records relating to the Graduate School of Social Work at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant.
Historical Note:
The University of Houston Graduate College of Social Work (GCSW) was established by the Texas State Legislature in 1967 with initial funding of $150,000. The “founding” faculty totaled seven individuals and twenty-six enrolled in the first class. The program was initially housed in a World War II Quonset Hut.
From these modest beginnings, the graduate program evolved over time to its current standing as a nationally recognized graduate social work program. The MSW (Master of Social Work) program has continually maintained its Council on Social Work Education professional accreditation since 1970 and in 1992 the PhD program was approved by the Texas State Coordinating Board.
Today, the College is housed in its own four-story building on campus and includes twenty-four fulltime faculty and approximately fifteen adjunct faculty. The faculty includes individuals whose writings have been considered for the Pulitzer prize as well as the 1997 Nobel Peace prize recipient – the GCSW is the only social work program in the world to have a Nobel laureate on faculty.
Today there are approximately 350 students enrolled in the MSW program with an additional 40 students in the PhD program. Students come from all walks of life, numerous states, and a number of international countries and they reflect the broad racial and ethnic diversity of our greater community.
The College’s academic offerings include the MSW and PhD with dual degree opportunities in business (Masters of Business Administration), law (Juris Doctorate), and Public Health (Masters in Public Health). Additionally the College offers certificates in gerontology, political social work, and trabajo social.
The College of Social Work offers wonderful international experiences including field placement opportunities and travel courses. Recently, students have traveled to England, Scotland, Costa Rica, Hong Kong, and mainland China for course work. To support the many international initiatives, the College has formal exchange agreements in place with City University of Hong Kong and the University of Wales.
More then 3,000 individuals have received their MSW degree from the University of Houston. The GCSW alumni continue to make significant differences in their clients’ lives, help formulate just social policies, while advocating and promoting justice for all people, no matter their stage in life.
Sources:
About Us, available from www.sw.uh.edu. 12 August 2009.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston; University of Houston. Graduate School of Social Work
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
This collection contain 2 boxes of records relating to the Graduate School of Social Work at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant. Materials include course information, stationary, certificates, invitations, program and workshop flyers, promotional material, published material, newsletters, reports, and commencement programs. This collection is arranged chronologically and alphabetically as necessary. Material ranges in date from the 1960s to 2009.
Detailed List of Contents
- undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1960s (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1970s (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
- 1980s (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 2000s (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Abstracts of the M.S.W. Student Research Projects, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Admission Brochures (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Center for Social Services Evaluation & Research (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Dean’s Awards Papers, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Field Instruction Manuals (Box 1, Folder 14)
- M.S.W. Admission Brochures, 1994-2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- M.S.W. Student Handbook, 1997-1998, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Ph.D in Social Work Brochure (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Report following Accreditation, March 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Self-Study Report submitted for Accreditation, January 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Social Work Papers (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Stationery (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Student Handbook, August 1, 1978, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)